Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/litorama (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Nursing

Languages

English (Full Professional) Filipino (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Registered Nurse

Nurse

Cardiac Medicine (Adult) (CMC)
Critical Care Registered Nurse

Honors-Awards

Class Valedictorian
Employee of the Month

Publications

Effects of Liberal Visitation on Anxiety, Satisfaction and Length of Stay Among Intensive Care Unit Patients

Lito Rama, MA, BSN, RN, CCRN-CMC

RN III Heart Transplant ICU at Texas Medical Center Houston, Texas

Summary

Critical Care Registered Nurse (CCRN) and Cardiac Medicine (CMC) certified nurse with 10 years hospital experience in the US, UK and the Philippines. Has more than 3 years nursing leadership experience including supervising clinical operations of 4 critical care nursing units in a Joint Commission accredited hospital. Was part of the Joint Commission Preparedness Team as member and chapter co-lead. BLS and ACLS Certified and ECMO trained nurse at Royal Brompton. Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt at Ateneo de Manila Business School.

Experience

Texas Medical Center
1 year 8 months

RN III COVID Critical Care Unit March 2020 - Present (3 months) Houston, Texas, United States

Provided care for patients on VV ECMO.

RN III Heart Transplant ICU October 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months) Houston, Texas Area

Employee of the Month (July 2019)

Royal Brompton & Harefield NHS Foundation Trust Adult ICU Nurse - Heart and Lung October 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 5 months) London, United Kingdom

Clinical exposure in Adult Intensive Care Unit, handling patients with postop heart surgeries and patients on VV ECMO. Member: Patient Diary Team (Quality Improvement Project) Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust Adult ICU Nurse May 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 5 months)

London, United Kingdom

Clinical exposure in Intensive Care Unit, handling patients with multi organ failure and patients with VV ECMO.

Under Continental TravelNurse Ltd

Chong Hua Hospital

1 year 5 months

Supervisor- Adult Critical Care/CNE September 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Cebu City, Philippines

Functions include staffing, scheduling, bed management and customer relations of 4 Critical Care Units. Project Lead for Nursing Standards of Care Group tasked to revise policies and work instructions for the Nursing Department. Facilitator- Evidenced Based Practice Research Workshop; BLS and ACLS Trainer.

Joint Commission International Implementer- Access and Continuity of Care

September 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Cebu City, Philippines

Asian Hospital and Medical Center 4 years 2 months

Charge Nurse Intensive Care Unit 2011 - March 2013 (2 years)

Metro Manila, Philippines

Supervised 30 RNs and 8 support staffs in a 19-bed ICU, managed daily operations of ICU including staffing, coaching, scheduling, evaluation, training and planning. Selected Contributions: Co-Lead, Assessment of Patient Chapter for the Joint Commission Internal Compliance Team; Policy Revisions

Critical Care Nurse February 2009 - March 2013 (4 years 2 months)

Metro Manila

Clinical exposures in Intensive Care Unit and Emergency Department.

Education

University of the Philippines
Master of Arts - MA, Nursing (2019)

West Visayas State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Nursing · (2007)

St George's, University of London (for students and alumni) Bachelor of Science (BSc), Health Care Practice (30 credits) · (2015)